Inventory to the James B. Webster papers
Hoover Institution Archives
James B. Webster papers
1894-2003
70027
Webster, James Benjamin, 1879-1929
43 manuscript boxes, 4 oversize boxes, 1 oversize folder, 1 envelope, 3 mounted photographs (21.8 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
The papers relate to theology, and to missionary activities and Christian education in China. They are comprised of diaries, correspondence, notebooks, writings, printed matter, photographs, and memorabilia.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1970.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
September 29, 1879 Born, Passumpsic, Vermont
1908-1912 Educational missionary in China
1912 September 25 Married Alta Newby in Chinkiang [Zhenjiang], China
1912-1915 Director of pastoral work and lecturer in Chinese and English, Shanghai Baptist College and Seminary
1915-1917 Attended Hartford Seminary Foundation where he received his PhD in Religious Education
1917-1925 Head of Department of Education and professor of Education, Shanghai College
1924 Acting dean, Shanghai College
1926-1928 Associate professor of Education, College of the Pacific, Stockton, California
1928 Completed research study on adolescent interests of Chinese youths
1929 December 8 Died, Stockton, California
Scope and Content of Collection
The collection documents J. B. Webster's work and life as a Christian missionary in China. The collection includes day books, correspondence, newspaper articles, writings, and other printed material from Webster's daily life. Webster lived in China for many years as a teacher and an administrator at Shanghai College. As a missionary and as an employee at the college, Webster worked to improve the Christian religious education movement, particularly in China, which included completing sociological studies of Chinese adolescents and writing on effective religious education techniques. The collection contains many examples of coursework and lesson plans for various classes at Shanghai colleges and other schools. Webster was interested in examining how sociological factors in the community and culture affected the acceptance and incorporation of religious education. The professional correspondence in the collection contains letters with fellow missionaries, superiors, coworkers at the Shanghai college, and students.
Apart from the documents and materials from Webster's professional life, the collection contains material from Webster's own education and personal life, such as documents from his time at seminary and family correspondence. The collection includes letters, writings, photographs, and biographical material of Alta Newby Webster, James B. Webster's wife, as well as family receipts from China, which reveal the day to day existence of the Webster family in China. Additionally, Webster kept diaries that describe his life and travels in China. A;though Webster died in the United States in 1929, and there is material in the collection that was created after his death, including correspondence and memorial materials.
The collection includes a significant number of photographs depicting the Webster family and other missionary families in China, students and instructors at Shanghai College, and scenery from Webster's travels around the country. Also included are black-and-white photographs taken by Webster that depict revolutionary troops attacking Qing Imperial forces. Webster had access to the battlefront on land and at sea.
Access Points
Education.; Education--China.; Missions--China.; China.; Missionaries.
Collection Contents
- Biographical material and photographs (Box-folder 1: 1)
- Diaries
  - 1908 (Box 1)
  - 1911 (Box 1)
  - 1912 (Box 1)
  - 1913 (Box 1)
  - 1914 (Box 1)
  - 1915 (Box 1)
  - 1916 (2 diaries) (Box 1)
  - 1918 (Box 1)
  - 1919 (Box 1)
  - 1920 (2 diaries) (Box 1)
  - 1921 (Box 1)
  - 1922 (Box 1)
  - 1923 (Box 1)
  - 1924 (Box 1)
  - 1925 (Box 1)
  - 1908 (Box 2)
  - "A Journal for Occasional Impressions" diary, 1908-1915 (Box 2)
  - Diary of trip to Canton and Hankow, 1910 (Box 2)
  - 1926 (2 diaries) (Box 2)
  - 1927 (2 diaries) (Box 2)
  - 1929 (3 diaries) (Box 2)
- Datebooks (Box 2)
  - 1917 (Box 2)
  - 1928 (Box 2)
  - 1931 (Box 2)
- Shanghai College handbook (3 items), 1924-1925 (Box 2)
- Passports and Chinese visas (Box 2)
  - James Benjamin Webster (3 items), 1919; 1924-1925 (Box 2)
  - Alta Newby Webster, 1924 (Box 2)
- Notebooks (3 items), 1931; undated (Box 2)
- Printed material, undated (Box-folder 2: 1)
- Correspondence
  - Anderson, Elam, 1921-1926 (Box-folder 3: 1)
  - Apperson, Mell, 1927-1928 (Box-folder 3: 2)
  - American University in Cairo, 1928-1929 (Box-folder 3: 3)
  - A, 1919 (Box-folder 3: 4)
  - Bromley, Charled and Jane, 1915-1925 (Box-folder 3: 5)
  - Barker, Charlotte, 1918-1927 (Box-folder 3: 6)
  - B, 1912-1928 (Box-folder 3: 7-8)
  - College of the Pacific, 1926-1928 (Box-folder 3: 9)
  - Chambers, China Baptist Publication Society, 1910-1915 (Box-folder 3: 10)
  - Crocker, 1909-1927 (Box-folder 3: 11)
  - Calvary Baptist Church, 1908-1914 (Box-folder 3: 12)
  - C, 1911-1928 (Box-folder 3: 13-15)
  - C, 1923-1928 (Box-folder 4: 1)
  - College Executive Committee minutes, 1923-1925 (Box-folder 4: 2)
  - College Executive Committee minutes and materials, 1917-1921 (Box-folder 4: 3)
  - Dennoyer-Geppert Co., 1928 (Box-folder 4: 4)
  - E. P. Dutton & Co., 1922-1927 (Box-folder 4: 5)
  - D, 1919-1928 (Box-folder 4: 6)
  - E, 1916-1928 (Box-folder 4: 7)
  - F, 1913-1925 (Box-folder 4: 8)
  - Ginn and Co., 1920-1928 (Box-folder 4: 9)
  - G, 1912-1928 (Box-folder 4: 10)
  - Galt, 1920-1929 (Box-folder 5: 1)
    Regarding American University of Cairo
  - H, 1912-1928 (Box-folder 5: 2-4)
  - Hipps, 1919-1927 (Box-folder 5: 5)
  - Hobart, 1908-1922 (Box-folder 5: 6)
  - Institute for Social and Economic Research, undated (Box-folder 5: 7)
  - Institute of Social and Religious Research, 1925-1929 (Box-folder 5: 8)
  - I, 1921-1929 (Box-folder 5: 9)
  - J, 1916-1925 (Box-folder 5: 10)
  - K, 1920-1928 (Box-folder 5: 11)
  - Love, J. F., 1916-1926 (Box-folder 5: 12-13)
  - L, 1913-1923 (Box-folder 6: 1)
  - Love conferences, notes and papers, 1919 (Box-folder 6: 2)
  - Cooperation on the Foreign Mission Field, 1913-1919 (Box-folder 6: 3)
  - Mitchell, S. C., 1913-1919 (Box-folder 6: 4)
  - M, 1913-1919 (Box-folder 6: 5)
  - National Council for Prevention of War, 1925-1928 (Box-folder 6: 6)
  - N, 1910-1927 (Box-folder 6: 7)
  - O, 1926 (Box-folder 6: 8)
  - Publishers, 1910-1928 (Box-folder 6: 9)
  - P, 1910-1928 (Box-folder 6: 10)
  - Runyan, Walter, 1925-1926 (Box-folder 6: 11)
  - Ray, T. B., 1914-1926 (Box-folder 6: 12-13)
  - R, 1914-1926 (Box-folder 7: 1)
  - Rawlinson, 1910-1928 (Box-folder 7: 2-3)
  - University of Richmond, 1923-1928 (Box-folder 7: 4)
  - Sheldon, 1908-1928 (Box-folder 7: 5-8)
  - Southern Baptist Convention, Foreign Mission Board, 1906-1926 (Box-folder 8: 1)
  - S, 1914-1927 (Box-folder 8: 2-3)
  - Tewkbury, 1912-1924 (Box-folder 8: 4)
  - T, 1912-1924 (Box-folder 8: 5)
  - W, 1915-1929 (Box-folder 8: 6-9)
  - Y, 1919-1925 (Box-folder 8: 10)
  - Z, 1918 (Box-folder 8: 10)
  - Assorted correspondece, 1926-1927 (Box-folder 9: 1)
  - Assorted correspondece, 1928-1929 (Box-folder 9: 2)
  - Assorted correspondece, 1929 (Box-folder 9: 3)
    Contains photographs
  - Assorted correspondece: Medical, 1922-1928 (Box-folder 9: 4)
- Notebooks
  - "Senior History,", undated (Box 9)
  - "Greek Notes on St. John,", 1907-1908 (Box 9)
  - "Old Testament Interpretation,", 1907-1908 (Box 9)
  - "Church History Notes,", 1907-1908 (Box 9)
  - "Dr. Hobart, Christian Ethics,", 1907-1908 (Box 9)
  - "Dr. Hobart, Church and Civil Law,", 1907-1908 (Box 9)
  - "Criticisms of New Testament and Old Testament,", 1907-1908 (Box 9)
  - Poetical books, Alta Newby lecture notes, undated (Box-folder 10: 1-2)
  - "Pastoral Theology,", 1907-1908 (Box 10)
- Examinations (Box 10)
  - "History of Education,", 1910 May (Box 10)
  - "History of Education,", 1916 March (Box 10)
  - "Fundamental Principles,", 1916 March (Box 10)
  - "Fundamental Principles #20,", 1916 March (Box 10)
  - "General Method,", 1916 March 9 (Box 10)
  - "General Method,", 1916 April 13 (Box 10)
- Notebooks (Box 10)
  - "Notes on New Testament and Old Testament,", 1910 (Box 10)
  - "Analysis of Herbarium Plants,", 1897 (Box 10)
  - "Chemistry,", undated (Box 10)
  - "Harmony of the Gospels,", 1903 (Box 10)
  - "Compositions,", undated (Box 10)
  - "Studies in the Epistles of John,", 1913 (Box 10)
  - "Studies in John's Gospels from Ch. 11:16,", 1913 (Box 10)
  - "Studies in John's Gospels to Ch. 11:16,", 1913 (Box 10)
  - "History of the Apolstolic Church,", 1913 (Box 10)
  - "Sewing notes and Diary,", 1905 (Box 10)
  - "Crozer Theological Seminary,", undated (Box 11)
  - "Notes from Teacher on Mateer's Lessons,", undated (Box 11)
  - "Old Testament Interpretation,", 1907-1908 (Box 11)
  - "Lesson and Lecture Notes,", undated (Box 11)
  - "Biology,", 1906 (Box 11)
  - "Crozer Theological Seminary,", 1906 (Box 11)
  - "Prophecy, Biblical Theology,", 1906 (Box 11)
  - "Assorted topics,", 1906 (Box 11)
  - "Bibliography in Systematic Theology, Church History,", 1908 (Box 11)
  - "Class Notes in Church History,", undated (Box 11)
  - "Isaiah, Dr. Taylor,", 1907-1908 (Box 11)
  - "Notes on Church History from September 1900 to June 1901,", undated (Box 11)
  - "Lesson and Lecture Notes,", undated (Box 11)
  - "Lesson and Lecture Notes,", undated (Boxes 12,47)
  - Notebook, 1898
  - "Crozer Theological Seminary, Volunteer band notes,", 1907-1908
  - "Set of Physical Culture Examples,", 1904-1905
  - "Speech Notes,", undated
  - "Dr. Evans, Religions,", undated
  - "Dr. Pollard, Homiletics,", 1906-1908
  - "Sermons, Activities,", 1894
  - "Compositions,", undated
  - "Assorted classwork," (2 items), 1906
  - "French and Carpenter Work in Hartford Night School,", 1916-1917
  - "History," (2 items), 1903-1905
- Memo book, 1897
- Cash book (account ledgers), 1902
- Cash book (account ledgers), 1912-1913
- Bible readings, 1902 (Box-folder 12: 1)
- Lecture notes, 1902 (Box-folder 12: 2)
- Religious education in school and church, 1924 (Box-folder 13: 1-2)
- Notes on Education 104, 1916-1924 (Box-folder 13: 3)
- Chinese correspondence, 1919-1924 (Box-folder 13: 4)
- South Dakota deeds, 1897-1899 (Box-folder 13: 5)
- Lesson plans, 1920 (Box-folder 13: 6-9)
- Notebooks (Box 14)
  - Education, 1922 (Box 14)
  - "Preschool Age, Infancy Years,", undated (Box 14)
  - "Preschool Age, Kindergarten Years,", undated (Box 14)
  - "Comprehensive Program of Religious Education in the Local Church,", undated (Box 14)
- Data regarding development of summer schools, 1918-1919 (Box-folder 14: 1)
- Printed materials on Chinese education, 1915-1917 (Box-folder 14: 2-6)
- Printed material on Chinese education (Contd.) (Box-folder 15: 1)
- Subject file
  - Esthetic, undated (Box-folder 15: 2)
  - Moral judgements, approval and disapproval, undated (Box-folder 15: 3)
  - Altruistic attitudes, undated (Box-folder 15: 4)
  - Religious attitudes
    - Belief in God, undated (Box-folder 15: 5)
    - Judgement of God's control of human affairs, undated (Box-folder 15: 6)
    - Attitude toward God, reasons, undated (Box-folder 15: 7)
    - Idea of prayer, undated (Box-folder 15: 8)
    - Judgement of value of prayer, reasons, undated (Box-folder 15: 9)
  - Social interests
    - Friendships, undated (Box-folder 15: 10)
    - Group activities, undated (Box-folder 15: 11)
    - Topics of conversation, undated (Box-folder 15: 12)
  - Sex interests, marriage, undated (Box-folder 15: 13)
  - Intellectual interests, Favorite reading material, undated (Box-folder 15: 14)
  - Study summary, undated (Box-folder 15: 14)
- Readings and articles from Alta Newby Webster, 1915 (Box-folder 15: 16)
- "Little Bennie Cowboy Stories,", undated (Box-folder 15: 17)
- Working notes for manuscript, 1924-1928 (Box-folder 16: 1)
- China Christian Education Association, 1917-1925 (Box-folder 16: 2)
- Writings for sermons and lessons, undated (Box-folder 16: 3)
- Printed material, undated (Box-folder 16: 4)
- Collected writings, undated (Box-folder 16: 5)
- A Survey of Chinese Adolescent Interests
  - Method, undated (Box-folder 16: 6)
  - Background, economic and religious, undated (Box-folder 16: 7)
  - Activities, undated (Box-folder 16: 8)
  - Play, undated (Box-folder 16: 9)
  - Definite abilities, undated (Box-folder 16: 10)
  - Vocation, undated (Box-folder 17: 1)
  - Property, undated (Box-folder 17: 2)
  - Animals, undated (Box-folder 17: 3)
  - Persons, heroes and aversions, undated (Box-folder 17: 4)
  - Introduction, undated (Box-folder 17: 5)
  - Fears, undated (Box-folder 17: 6)
- Church history, foreign missions, and history of Methodism, undated (Box-folder 17: 7)
- Pentateuch and historical books, undated (Box-folder 17: 8)
- Church history notes, 1906-1907 (Box-folder 17: 9)
- Shanghai College, Education department notes and data, 1923-1925 (Box-folder 17: 10)
- James B. Webster Memorial Fund, 1931 (Box-folder 17: 11)
- Condoldences regarding death of James B. Webster, 1929-1930 (Box-folder 17: 12)
- Department of Education, College Curriculum Committee, 1918-1919 (Box-folder 18: 1)
- Problems of Oriental education, notes, 1927 (Box-folder 18: 2)
- Oriental civilization material, 1927-1928 (Box-folder 18: 3)
- Oriental civilization, clippings and images, 1927-1928 (Box-folder 18: 4)
- Printed material, 1926-1928 (Box-folder 18: 5)
- Psychology notes and education binder, 1926-1928 (Box 18)
- Visual education in religion, 1922-1923 (Box-folder 19: 1)
- Notes on planning education in China, 1919-1920 (Box-folder 19: 2-3)
- Education Department potential courses, 1921 (Box-folder 19: 4)
- Data on development of education debt at colleges, 1918 (Box-folder 19: 5)
- Theological education notes, 1918-1920 (Box-folder 19: 6)
- College community cultivation, 1919-1920 (Box-folder 19: 7)
- History of religious education movement in China, undated (Box-folder 19: 8-11)
  Folder 10 includes photographs
- Christian Education and the National Consciousness in China, manuscript, 1922 (Box-folder 20: 1-2)
- Notes and manuscripts on Mohtse, 1927 (Box-folder 20: 3)
- Motives, ideals and values in Christian education in China, 1917-1920 (Box-folder 20: 4-5)
- Religious Education Committee materials, 1919-1920 (Box-folder 20: 6-7)
- "Tabulation of Interest" records-Girls, 1919-1925 (Box-folder 20: 8)
- "Tabulation of Interest" records-Boys, 1919-1925 (Box-folder 20: 9)
- Correspondence regarding adolescent interest survey, 1925 (Box-folder 20: 10)
- Printed material for Appendix, 1929 (Box-folder 21: 1)
- Biographical file, 1908-1929 (Box-folder 21: 2)
- Pi Gamma Mu, social science magazine, 1927-1928 (Box-folder 21: 3)
- Pacific Coast Oriental contacts, 1926 (Box-folder 21: 4)
- Presbyterian Ministers' Fund, 1916-1928 (Box-folder 21: 5)
- James B. Webster writings and lectures, 1918-1924 (Box-folder 21: 6)
- Psychology course materials, 1926-1927 (Box-folder 21: 7-8)
- Problems of Oriental Education, research materials, 1922-1926 (Box-folder 21: 9)
- Interrace studies and international education, plans and memoranda, 1923-1926 (Box-folder 21: 10)
- Forms used in the Human Genetics Division, John Hopkins University, undated (Box-folder 21: 11)
- Articles in Preparation, 1916-1926 (Box-folder 21: 12)
- A Survey of Chinese Adolescent Interests, 1925-1926 (Box-folder 22: 1-4)
- Education in China, printed material, 1921-1922 (Box-folder 22: 5)
- Popular material, Psychology education, 1920-1925 (Box-folder 22: 6)
- Clippings on education and social condition in Japan, 1919 (Box-folder 22: 7)
- Clippings on education in China and miscellaneous, 1920 (Box-folder 22: 8)
- Clippings on education in the west, 1917-1920 (Box-folder 22: 9)
- Chapel Talk materials, 1920 (Box-folder 22: 10)
- Notes from Crozer Theological Seminary, 1923 (Box-folder 22: 11)
- Course materials, Education 107, 1923-1924 (Box-folder 23: 1-4)
- Honolulu conference materials, 1924-1925 (Box-folder 23: 5)
- Curriculum correlation, 1923-1925 (Box-folder 23: 6)
- Course materials, Education A, 1924 (Box-folder 23: 7)
- A Survey of Chinese Adolescents, 1928 (Box-folder 23: 8)
- A Survey of Chinese Adolescents (Contd.) (Box-folder 24: 1-2)
- Union Academy statements and correspondence, 1911-1913 (Box-folder 24: 3)
- Religious education, printed material, 1914-1928 (Box-folder 24: 4)
- Christian industry in China, National Christian Council, 1924-1929 (Box-folder 24: 5)
- Course materials, Education 113 and 114 Group Method book, 1923-1924 (Box-folder 24: 6-8)
- Course materials, Education 113 and 114 Group Method book (Contd.) (Box-folder 25: 1-2)
- Psychology material on the student strike, 1919-1920 (Box-folder 25: 3-4)
- Sunday school nature study lessons, undated (Box-folder 25: 5)
- Psychology of religion data, 1919-1920 (Box-folder 25: 6)
- Financial records (Box-folder 25-26)
  - Receipts from Shanghai, 1917-1921 (Box-folder 25: 7-8)
  - Checkbooks, 1908-1913 (Box-folder 26: 1-2)
  - China receipts and statements, 1907-1918 (Box-folder 26: 3-8)
- Subject file
  - Art and literature, 1913-1914 (Box-folder 27: 1)
  - Christianity and industry in China, 1923 (Box-folder 27: 2)
  - China, general writings, 1919-1925 (Box-folder 27: 3)
  - Publisher correspondence, 1912 (Box-folder 27: 4)
  - Christian education in China, 1912-1925 (Box-folder 27: 5)
  - Maps depicting mission stations in China, undated (Box-folder 27: 6)
  - China's foreign relations, 1910-1911 (Box-folder 27: 7)
  - Famine of 1910-1911 (Box-folder 27: 8)
  - Government, 1910-1914 (Box-folder 27: 9)
  - Politics and economics, 1912-1913 (Box-folder 27: 10)
  - Religion, 1912-1913 (Box-folder 27: 11)
  - Union Educational Commission of China, minutes, 1911-1914 (Box-folder 27: 12)
  - Science and education, 1911 (Box-folder 27: 13)
- Writings
  - "Pawnshops and Opium in China,", undated (Box-folder 27: 14)
  - "The Capture of Purple Mountain and the Fall of Nanking,", 1911 (Box-folder 27: 15)
  - "The Fall of Nanking,", circa 1911 (Box-folder 27: 16)
  - "A Glimpse of the Advance on Peking,", 1912 (Box-folder 27: 17)
  - "Things Chinese,", 1913 (Box-folder 27: 18)
- Miscellaneous clippings, 1911-1913 (Box-folder 27: 19)
- Photographs
  - 28 photos of scenes of the Chinese Revolution and of daily life and cultural sites in China, 1911-1912 (Envelope A)
  - 3 mounted photos, 9 oversize, 4 prints, undated (Map case case)
- Incremental materials, 1902-2003
  - Photographs, 1902-1930 (Box 28)
    Includes miscellaneous revolution photographs from Chongqing and Nanjing (1911), early photographs of James Webster, portraits of James Webster and Alta Newby Webster, Webster family photographs, other missionaries in China, and cartes de visite of Chinese students
  - Correspondence, 1913-1926 (Box-folder 29: 1-6)
  - "Little Bennie Cowboy Stories," manuscripts, 1923 (Box-folder 29: 7)
  - Biographical materials, 1929 (Box-folder 29: 8)
  - Mission Board correspondence, incoming and outgoing, 1908-1926 (Box-folder 30: 1-3)
  - Mission information, 1920-1935 (Box-folder 30: 4-5)
  - Letters from E. M. Jeter, photocopies, 1917-1923 (Box-folder 30: 6-10)
  - Binder of materials on Alta Almira Newby, 1909-1938 (Box 31)
    Includes transcripts of letters, photocopies of photographs, and biogrpahical materials
  - James B. Webster and Alta A. Newby biographical materials (Box 31)
    Relates mostly to their wedding and honeymoon
  - "Travels with Martha Esther Webster 1915-1930" (Box 31)
  - Correspondence of Carleton Mabee and Esther Webster Howse regarding China, 1924; 1995-1996 (Box 31)
  - Correspondence, 1904-1914 (Box 32)
    Scope and Contents note
    Includes photographs and negatives. Includes correspondence of wife, Alta Newby
  - Correspondence, 1904-1914 (Box-folder 33: 1-3)
  - Letters to Alta Newby from James B. Webster, 1911-1912 (Box-folder 33: 4-5)
  - Letters to Alta Newby from James B. Webster, 1911-1912 (Box-folder 34: 1-4)
  - Correspondence, 1912-1957 (Box-folder 34: 5)
  - Correspondence, 1912-1957 (Box 45)
  - Correspondence, 1912-1957 (Box 46)
  - Chinese Bible, 1914 (Box 35)
  - Chinese Hymnal prepared by Rev. H. Blodget and Rev. C. Goodrich, 1909 (Box 35)
  - Crozer Theological Seminary bulletin, 1930 (Box 35)
    Includes tribute to James B. Webster
  - Songs of Cathay compiled by T. Z. Koo, undated (Box 35)
  - Shanghai College yearbook, 1925 (Box 35)
  - Alta Newby Webster guestbook, 1923-1934 (Box 36)
  - Interests of Chinese Students. Vol. 1 Studies in Education and Psychology by James B. Webster, 1932 (Box 36)
  - "The Story of the Univeristy of Shanghai from the Year 1906 to the Year 1934" (Box 36)
  - Glass lantern slides depicting scenes from children's stories, undated (Box 36)
  - Ribbons and medals from Butte [Montana] Miners Union and Western Federation of Miners, undated (Box 36)
  - Photographs of Webster family and others, 1922-1923 (Box-folder 37: 1)
  - Materials used by Alta Newby Webster in her teaching and supervising, 1941; undated (Box-folder 37: 2-3)
  - German mark and list of Chinese dynasties, undated (Box-folder 37: 4)
    Hand painted Chinese poster moved to Box 44
  - Seals taken from doors of the Baldwin Memorial school after forced evacuation during riots and cash ticket, 1906 (Box-folder 37: 5)
  - University of the Pacific correspondence, 1926 (Box-folder 37: 6)
  - Alta Newby speech notes, undated (Box-folder 37: 7)
  - Copper reliefs and sketches, undated (Box-folder 37: 8)
  - Photographs depicting Shanghai College and families of instructors, 1925 (Box-folder 37: 9)
  - Alta Newby Webster correspondence, narrative of sixty-mile walk through China, and copies of photographs, 1907-1912 (Box-folder 37: 10)
  - Mali Lee [Ma Li] letters and photographs before and during the war in Shanghai and Nanking, 1937-1938 (Box-folder 37: 11)
  - Alta Newby Webster commemorative diploma from Wesleyan College, 1949 (Box-folder 37: 12)
  - Notes and observations, undated (Box-folder 37: 13)
  - Letter from Mirian Mabee, undated (Box-folder 37: 14)
  - Missionary education in China printed materials and clippings, 1910-1923 (Box-folder 37: 15)
  - Photographs of the Webster and Newby families, 1912-1914 (Box-folder 37: 16)
  - Writings and research materials, 1929; 2003 (Box-folder 37: 17)
  - 3 glass plate negatives (Box 37)
  - Postcards from China and the United States, 1910-1922 (Box 38)
  - Postcards from China and the United States, 1903-1927 (Box 39)
  - Chinese vocabulary flash cards, undated (Box 39)
  - Notebook of Alta Newby Webster filled with inspirational clippings and jokes, undated (Box 39)
  - Soong, Maying. The Art of Chinese Paper Folding for Young and Old, 1948 (Box 39)
  - James B. Webster biographical materials, 1929-1930 (Box 39)
    Includes condolences and memorial service pamphlets
  - Letters from the Hoover Company regarding donation of vaccuums to Shanghai College, 1923-1924 (Box 39)
  - Classroom materials and correspondence, 1949 (Box 39)